<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The IoTe Project on Rusty Eddy</title>
    <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iote/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The IoTe Project on Rusty Eddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.rustyeddy.com/iote/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Iot Hub</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot-project/hub/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot-project/hub/</guid>
      <description>What Does OG Hub Do? In a nutshell the Hub gathers environmental data from a network of Collection Stations using the well known MQTT Messaging protocol. The hub feeds the data to the Oraganic Gardner application, streams it real-time to dashboard users via Websockets and caches the data in RAM.
How Does the Hub Work? The Hub is a small, fast server written in Go with the following dependencies:
 Go&amp;rsquo;s built-in HTTP Server to serve HTML Go&amp;rsquo;s built=in HTTP Server to serve REST API Websocket Library for real time data to dashboard MQTT Eclipse MQTT Library  The software running on the Hub can be called a Micro-service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Real-time Dashboard</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iote/dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iote/dashboard/</guid>
      <description>Dashboard WebApp The snapshot of the dashboard above is a WebUI served by the Hub displaying the real time values for temperature, humidity and uptime. Actually three of the four stations in the screen shot above are mocked using mosquitto_pub. See the &amp;ldquo;Mocking&amp;rdquo; section of the Hub section of the website.
Recieving Data The dashboard recieves all of it&amp;rsquo;s data from the Hub which in turn streams the data to the dashboard over Websockets in real-time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection Station</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot-project/collection-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot-project/collection-station/</guid>
      <description>Publishing Sensor Data The idea is pretty simple really: build a network of wireless battery powered devices to gather environmental data such as temprature, moisture, light levels, etc. The collected data will then be published via MQTT wirelessly to the Hub.
Types of Published Data The planned data types to be published by the system are concerned with the following types of sensors.
 Temprature Humidity Moisture Light Barometric Pressure  Technically any type of data could be published and collected however we are focused on the type of data our OG application will use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Automation</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iote/cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iote/cloud/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Automation Cloud support extends the reach of the data globally allowing access to both real-time and historical datas, it also expands the length data can be kept. Rather than a couple weeks to a month per hub, the data loaded in the cloud can be persisted for years at very low cost.
Entire fleets of hubs can be managed from the cloud console making it easy to manage, monitor and update large deployments of not only sensor station but also the hubs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An IoT Dashboard Written with Vue</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iote/iot-dashboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iote/iot-dashboard/</guid>
      <description>This version of this dashboard is going to be a simple one page dashboard.
Responsive means Mobile First Vue is Reactive Vue 3 Setup with Vite </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding the REST API to IoT Gateway</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iote/iot-gateway-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iote/iot-gateway-rest/</guid>
      <description>Previously we have added MQTT to the IoT Gateway as part of the Organic Gardner Project. This gave the gateway the ability to collect and store a lot of environmental data from sensors all over the place.
Now we need to provide a way for others programs, like the IoT Dashboard access that data via a REST API.
Implementing a RESTful API The RESTful API convention is exteremely popular, well supported and is perfectly suited to providing access to the sensor data that has been collected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding MQTT to the IoT Gateway</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iote/iot-gateway-mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iote/iot-gateway-mqtt/</guid>
      <description>This page marks the beginning of the Organic Gardner (OG) IoT Project Milestone 1 development! If you want to program along but have not yet worked with the Go programming language check this intro: Getting ready to Go.
A Brief About MQTT MQTT is the messaging protocol that a Collector will use to periodically publish sensor data (like temperature and humidity) to the IoT Gateway. MQTT will also be used to signal when the Control Station or Controller will respond to commands to turn a sprinkler pump on or off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Self Watering Garden</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 10:32:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot-project/</guid>
      <description>What is this project about? Organic Gardner (OG) is an automated irrigation system that gathers soil moisture levels from various sections of a garden then uses that data to activate the garden sprinkler system. Done right, this will eliminate both over and under watering. Likewise there will no longer be any need to program the watering schedule with confusing sprinkler menus.
 Although she does not know it yet, my wife will volunteer her succulent garden for testing!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
