<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>raspberry-pi on Rusty Eddy</title>
    <link>http://rustyeddy.com/tags/raspberry-pi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in raspberry-pi on Rusty Eddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rustyeddy.com/tags/raspberry-pi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Camera and Multiple Ports</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/raspberry-pi-camera-multiple-ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/raspberry-pi-camera-multiple-ports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I started bumbling around trying to figure the best way to stream
[live video from a moving vehicle], I found that the Raspberry Pi
camera is capable of producing filtered versions of the images it is
producing, through &lt;em&gt;video ports&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino Motor Control Software</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/arduino-motor-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/arduino-motor-controllers/</guid>
      <description>Pictured about is the OSEPP v2 Motor Shield which can be used as a functional replacement to the Adafruit v2 motorshield, the motorshield I recommend.
 Source code can be found here http://github.com/mobilerobot-io/arduino/ within the src/mctl directory.
 Arduino Motorsheild and Distributed Controls The software in the repository is to be loaded on an Arduino with either an Adafruit v2 Arduino or OSEPP 6612 MotorShield. The software accepts commands as incoming text strings from one of several possible serial inputs; UART, RF Radio, Blue Tooth, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inexpensive Motor Controllers for Arduino and Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/motor-controlor-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/motor-controlor-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I prefer to use an Arduino with a Motor Controller over say a
Raspberry Pi with a motor-controller.  I believe the Arudino has
better support for dedicated Real-time software vs. the Raspberry Pi
and as a superior platform for general computing including running
Control Software.  This is how we do it on the West side &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/ansible/</guid>
      <description>Ansible is a very powerful yet simple, in all its complexity. It is a wonderful tool that I get frequent use of. It&amp;rsquo;s real home I suppose is in the larger corporation devops world, it is wonderfully well suited to a mid sized IoT environment.
A Few Highlight about Ansible Scripts are Accurate and Repeatable Create Playbooks that combine a series of specific roles to get define specific roles the configuration steps to get a desired outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>