<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The IoT Project on Rusty Eddy</title>
    <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The IoT Project on Rusty Eddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adding the REST API to IoT Gateway</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot/iot-gateway-rest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot/iot-gateway-rest/</guid>
      <description>Previously we have added MQTT to the IoT Gateway as part of the Organic Gardner Project. This gave the gateway the ability to collect and store a lot of environmental data from sensors all over the place.
Now we need to provide a way for others programs, like the IoT Dashboard access that data via a REST API.
Implementing a RESTful API The RESTful API convention is exteremely popular, well supported and is perfectly suited to providing access to the sensor data that has been collected.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding MQTT to the IoT Gateway</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot/iot-gateway-mqtt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot/iot-gateway-mqtt/</guid>
      <description>This page marks the beginning of the Organic Gardner (OG) IoT Project Milestone 1 development! If you want to program along but have not yet worked with the Go programming language check this intro: Getting ready to Go.
A Brief About MQTT MQTT is the messaging protocol that a Collector will use to periodically publish sensor data (like temperature and humidity) to the IoT Gateway. MQTT will also be used to signal when the Control Station or Controller will respond to commands to turn a sprinkler pump on or off.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Self Watering Garden</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 10:32:26 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/iot-project/</guid>
      <description>What is this project about? Organic Gardner (OG) is an automated irrigation system that gathers soil moisture levels from various sections of a garden then uses that data to activate the garden sprinkler system. Done right, this will eliminate both over and under watering. Likewise there will no longer be any need to program the watering schedule with confusing sprinkler menus.
 Although she does not know it yet, my wife will volunteer her succulent garden for testing!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
