<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Field Notes on Rusty Eddy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Field Notes on Rusty Eddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Webdev Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/webdev/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/webdev/</guid>
      <description>This section of my website is a collection of processes and best practices regarding software development. I gather them here, in an attempt to remember and formalize.
Over the years, I have collected a set of practices and certain software practices and patterns. When I work for a client these practices will be documented as part of the development process.
This section of my website is dedicated to the development of web sites and apps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Development Process</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/website-development-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/website-development-process/</guid>
      <description>Measurable Goal To be truely effective and objective we need to be clear about an outcome or desired effect of every project we take one. It is best to select a single overiding, measurable goal.
That goal should be measurable, it could be a dollar amount in sales, a number of email subscribers (or InstaTwitter followers) or any number of other things.
A Dynamic System The more specific or goals become the better we are able to ascertain the success of our project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/resources/</guid>
      <description> MicroServices  JavaScript  Learn JavaScript ~ EC2015 Axios Cheatsheet  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/software-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/software-development/</guid>
      <description>moni/
Most of the questions above have a pretty short answer, if you want to organize them I can supply answers. By separating them into individual threads, or a doc of some type. Answering here would get messy.
Here are couple high level comments I have after looking over your list.
 Many of the technologies you mention are either/or choices, you pick one over the other. This is especially true with anything JavaScript related because everything changes on a monthly basis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Website Design and Developers, What is the Difference</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/website-roles/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/website-roles/</guid>
      <description>Should I hire a web designer or web developer and what is the difference?
It is kinda funny, in the rest of the tech world the terms designer and developer mean distinctive things, and aside from a few rare unicorns, they very different roles.
Developers write code and make things work, designers make things look good. But for one reason and another, in the world of Web these skills do infact overlap to some extent, and in some rare cases a single individual is skilled at both aesthetic presentation and the practical application of abstract logic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Gstreamer to create an RTSP Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/gstreamer-rtsp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/gstreamer-rtsp-server/</guid>
      <description>Of it earlier this month I set out to start streaming video From the CSI camera, that is a raspberry pie camera, From a moving vehicle for the vehicles guidance and navigation.
I was surprised to find the the whole world is streaming video is Incredibly complex, NFL 2019 we do not have A solution that is easy universally adopted.
TLDR; Gstreamer RTSP Pipeline We are streaming our video from a Raspberry Pi Camera (CSI) attached to, either a Raspberry Pi or a Jetson Nano, GST extracts the video from the CSI camera using a custom driver (raspicamsrc or nvargussrc) for the RPi or Nano respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebRTC What is it?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/webrtc-what-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/webrtc-what-is-it/</guid>
      <description>WebRTC stands for Web Realtime Communications. Yea, I know you can Google too, now let&#39;s ask, &amp;ldquo;What does that mean?&amp;quot;.
Realtime Communication Generally speaking we all, intuitively know what Real Time means, it is a sense of what is happening now. OK, that is reasonable, after all it is how we live the majority of our lives.
Communication &amp;ldquo;Topologies&amp;rdquo;  One to one One to many many to many many to one?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GStreamer building realtime media pipelines</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/gstreamer-building-streaming-pipelines/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/gstreamer-building-streaming-pipelines/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Video is Complicated</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/streaming-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/streaming-video/</guid>
      <description>I need to stream live video from a moving vehical with a connected camera and a possibly connected wifi.
Live High Resolution Video Video will stream from the vehicle to be picked up by video consumers and processed as required. Examples of consumers are Live Video Display on our (Webapp), OpenCV for vision algoritms.
High Demand For Low Resolution It turns out that computer vision alogrithms typically run quite a bit faster on lower resolution images, the additional information from these hi-res images can slow down the type of algorithms we are interested in by many factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Video Protocols</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/streaming-video-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/streaming-video-protocols/</guid>
      <description>rtp rtsp rtmp hlsl mjpeg mpeg-dash mpeg jpeg  RTP ~ Real Time Protocol Actually holds payloads containing arbitrary, but time/delay sensitive media (audio, video, live conversations, etc). Incorporates enough controls to allow for network congestion, reciever compensation and more.
RTSP What it is and How to use it Real Time Streaming Protocol (RTSP)
General consensus says that RTSP is a good choice for low latency, local area networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Video Tools</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/streaming-video-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/streaming-video-tools/</guid>
      <description>The grandparents of streaming video, and snapshots, read, writing and transcoding video and single frame images are ffmpeg, vlc and gstreamer.
Other platforms, such as the wildly cool and inexpensive Raspberry Pi and attached CSI Camera (Raspberry Pi Camera) have thier own set of utilities: like raspivid. Or the NVidia Nano with it&#39;s gst-streamer plugins and nvgst-capture/nvgst-playback utilies.
 This writting is as of March 2019
 GStreamer Complex, Flexible, Future Proof GStreamer really complex pipelines but insanely flexible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Camera and Multiple Ports</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/raspberry-pi-camera-multiple-ports/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/raspberry-pi-camera-multiple-ports/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I started bumbling around trying to figure the best way to stream
[live video from a moving vehicle], I found that the Raspberry Pi
camera is capable of producing filtered versions of the images it is
producing, through &lt;em&gt;video ports&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Live Video on a Local Lan Vs. Internet</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/streaming-video-local-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/streaming-video-local-network/</guid>
      <description>differences in local vs. internet and streaming video
  live stream vs. video on demand
  what does real time mean?
  what to do with late packets?
  UDP vs. TCP in the local network
  RTP and UDP
  RTP and RTCP
  RTP and RTSP
  RTP and Multicast
  Tools used
  TODO: workflowy outline</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About MicroServices and Distributed Systems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/about-distributed-systems-and-micro-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/about-distributed-systems-and-micro-services/</guid>
      <description>I am very much dedicated to building distributed, micro-service style systems. I prefer to piece solutions together based on lean, efficient, best of breed components.
More Complex? Many rightly claim that a distributed system increases the complexity over the monolith, and it is true that communicaiton boundaries must be explicitly created, and that communications between the boundarys becomes a potential for failure, or reduced reliability that tightly couple systems do not have to deal with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Graphics with Canva</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/design-graphics-with-canva/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/design-graphics-with-canva/</guid>
      <description>Canva is a very simple yet powerful graphics art tool, for non-graphic artists. You can to on there and create free stuff, or, if you are a pro and create graphics all the time, you can optin for a reasonable montly fee.
I created the RedEye logo for the Mobile Robot Project using Canva, it took me 15 minutes, including remembering my forgotten password.
There are a ton of templates, graphics and photos that can be easily drag-n-dropped into place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using CMake</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/cmake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/cmake/</guid>
      <description>CMake is a growingly popular method for generating Makefile files depending on the build computer being used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/ansible/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/ansible/</guid>
      <description>Ansible is a very powerful yet simple, in all its complexity. It is a wonderful tool that I get frequent use of. It&#39;s real home I suppose is in the larger corporation devops world, it is wonderfully well suited to a mid sized IoT environment.
A Few Highlight about Ansible   Create Playbooks that defines the configuration of a target architecture.
  Ansible is Idempotent meaning it defines the the desired outcome, it is up to Ansible to make that outcome real.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adafruit Music Maker mp3 Sheild</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/adafruit-music-maker-mp3-sheild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/adafruit-music-maker-mp3-sheild/</guid>
      <description>The shield is driven by an SPI connection with the Arduino and relies on an SD card with music files on it to play. Must determine how to play streaming audio, then we&#39;ll have something neat!
Link to the documentation.
The shield can also be jumpered and booted into Midi Mode and turned into a drum machine or a Garageband type of play along.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenCV</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/opencv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/opencv/</guid>
      <description>Building OpenCV is quite a task, so if you are just getting started, or do not need something in more recent versions, then by all means use your OSs package management facility to install OpenCV, otherwise here is a list of things that I did to get the latest version of OpenCV built so I could infuse it with some GStreamer to deliver streaming video to our CV algorithms.
Installing on Linux and a MacOS Install cmake to build these things from scratch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Problem Statement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/problem-statement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/problem-statement/</guid>
      <description>To research enough to clearly solve the problem is alot.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>