<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software on Rusty Eddy</title>
    <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/categories/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software on Rusty Eddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.rustyeddy.com/categories/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Red Eye Video Server</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/notes/redeye/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/notes/redeye/</guid>
      <description>The Red Eye project is a service definition rapper around inexpensive cameras attached to inexpesive micro-controllers that take pretty good video.
The video streams are built using the GStreamer library. The camera native capabilities are used to extract as high quailty, realtime images possible.
The video streams will be consumed by one or more sinks, including but not limited to Files, cloud storage, High Def Display and Computer Vision libraries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skid Steering</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/notes/skid-steering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/notes/skid-steering/</guid>
      <description>Skid steering basics
Based on fixed direction wheels[1] or tracks There are two groups or sides of wheels: left and right All wheels in a group MUST always point in the same direction All wheels in a group MUST always rotate at the same rate Direction is determined by the speed of the two wheel groups To move straight all motors rotate at the same rate Forward and Reverse are determined by positive and negative values Turning is achieved by varying the throttle on the right and left Example The Skidder class has the following API, as you can see all of the movements we desire can be accomplished with a single API call skidder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Raspberry Pi Motor Control Software</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/notes/rpi-motor-control-service/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/notes/rpi-motor-control-service/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;TODO ~ replace image with one of the Raspberry Pi Controller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This software adds a Skid Steer motor control software to the
&lt;a href=&#34;http://github.com/mobilerobot-io/rpid&#34;&gt;Raspberry Pi Device Server&lt;/a&gt;
device server.  RPID adds motor controls accessible via both MQTT and
REST APIs, as well as directly with the Skidder python library.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MQTT For Controllor Communication</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/notes/mqtt-comm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/notes/mqtt-comm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The MQTT message bus is a simple but critical element of our MBR
software design.  MQTT provides what is known as a &lt;em&gt;publish/suscribe&lt;/em&gt;
or &lt;em&gt;pubsub&lt;/em&gt; communications model.  This model of machine to machine
communication has some attractive benefits for realtime driving
algorithms that we will discuss in this post.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control Station Display</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/notes/touch-screen-display/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/notes/touch-screen-display/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are going to build a simple control station that begins with a
Raspberry Pi and connected &lt;em&gt;7 inch touchscreen tablet&lt;/em&gt;.  I have it
setup in &amp;ldquo;kiosk mode&amp;rdquo;, which is basically full page chrome without the
tabs and tool bars etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TLV the Type Length Vector Protocol</title>
      <link>http://www.rustyeddy.com/notes/tlv-and-realitime-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.rustyeddy.com/notes/tlv-and-realitime-communication/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TLV is a very simple communication protocol that can be used to send
messages around a complex, distributed system.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
