<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How to run a stress free software project with predictable results on Rusty Eddy</title>
    <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How to run a stress free software project with predictable results on Rusty Eddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rustyeddy.com/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Discovery and MVP</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/discovery-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/discovery-session/</guid>
      <description>This consists of one or more customer discovery sessions, where all users and owners of the software will be interviewed for their expectations, needs and desires from the upcoming software project.
The customer discovery is then turned into user stories, which are then vetted to collect the user stories. Then they are broke down into tasks that are Small, autonmous and measurable.
The test that we come up with must be completed within a day or two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organinizing Software Projects with Kanban</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/kanban/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/kanban/</guid>
      <description>Expect the task list to be ever evolving. During the discovery session and defining the MVP you will begin to identify an initial set of tasks, and as the project precedes additional tasks will be realized.
Whenever and however a new task is identified, that task will be placed on the kanban board in the to do list section.
The item is ordered in the to do list according to its priority amongst the other tasks on the to do list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance Tests</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/notes/acceptance-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/notes/acceptance-tests/</guid>
      <description>One of the first things that ought to be done, but seldom get the attention it needs are the specific criteria that must be met to make the customer/user happy.
We are going to call this group of criteria the projects Acceptance Test. Ideally all acceptance tests can be automated with software, however they may be cases that manual intervention is required to conduct an entire set of Acceptance tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acceptance Tests</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/acceptance-tests/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/acceptance-tests/</guid>
      <description>Todo give some good examples of acceptance tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fork in the Code</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/fork-in-the-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/fork-in-the-code/</guid>
      <description> Git is a tool used by most, now. Git Workflow Github is a service built around git. git version control github issues github authentication github web hooks and api github pull requests github discussions github actions github wikis </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Process</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/release-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/release-process/</guid>
      <description>Once the code has been commited, an action will be taken to compile a latest version of the code into a tarball and hoist upon the release server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software is a Team Sport</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/team-sport/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/team-sport/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt;&amp;lt; HEAD
Software is a sport. Software as a team sport. Like all other teams, it must act as a functional support system. While many teams have a Quaterback or The Driver, There is unquestionably a large number of personnel all built with specific functions to successfully deliver or accomplish the goal of the team.
No difference with software.
Programmers and sometimes management or maybe an architect are the center of attention most of the time, There is a specific need for a diverse set of skills and experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making a Commitment</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/making-a-commitment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/making-a-commitment/</guid>
      <description>This document takes us to the point we have new code that has been peer reviewed, tested and now ready to become part of production.
TODO: Walk through, merging the branch and ticking off a nightly build to the repository.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimum Viable Product (MVP)</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/mvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/mvp/</guid>
      <description>The MVP, as its name suggests, should be the thing that makes The customer happy and can be delivered in the shortest period of time by the development team.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools and Workflow</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/tools-and-workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/tools-and-workflow/</guid>
      <description>Tools and Workflow For this article we are going to use Github, Which is a pretty standard part of my workflow.
As many of you may know git is a software version control system. Github wraps a lot of very useful features around the source control tool like:
 Git soure control Github issues for tracking features, requests and bugs Kanban board to visually track and manage Actions: Automated debugs Pull requests for code review before committing Static HTTP server for web page documentation Release packages  With these capabilities built into github we have pretty much everything that we need to run our entire software development process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>