<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Predictable Software Development on Rusty Eddy</title>
    <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Predictable Software Development on Rusty Eddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rustyeddy.com/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Clearity with Objectives and Milestones</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/clarity-objectives-milestones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/clarity-objectives-milestones/</guid>
      <description>How to Start   It is amazing how many complex and expensive software projects start with nothing more than a proof of concept. Objective   The first things above all is to state a clear, measurable objective. It should go without saying, the objective must also be reasonable.  Believe it or not, I have seen people post (on Upwork) jobs asking to create a Facebook Like website for $500.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organization with Version Control</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/organization-with-version-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/organization-with-version-control/</guid>
      <description>With at least a first slash at some milestones and goals that the entire team can huddle around. Let&amp;#39;s roll up our sleeves and get Buzzin!   But before we scatter to our cubes and bury our heads behind terminals, let&amp;#39;s all agree to get on the same page by choosing a set of tools (manual or electric) that we all are going to agree on using in a consistent and collaborative way!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piece of Mind with Testing</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/piece-of-mind-with-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/piece-of-mind-with-testing/</guid>
      <description>Good Job Keeping Files Organized  Next Up Treating Your Customers with Respect (They will appreciate it!)   Please: DO NOT recruite your customers to be your QA department. Especially if they are unanaware, thinking they are getting a usable piece of software.  It is time to start adopting a Test Driven Development (TDD) mindset. Even if you are knee deep into an existing development project, get started building out our TDD now!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Hassle Updates with CI/CD</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/no-hassle-updates-with-cicd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/no-hassle-updates-with-cicd/</guid>
      <description>Glad to hear testing is going well!  Now it is time to Get the soccer out to the users For the real test. This test is measurable Buyer customers feedback Good Software is Continually Improved   The greater the success software Is directly proportionate to The number of features that are requested As well as the number of bugs that are found.  &amp;gt; Bug reports means your softwar is getting used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Feedback Loop Bugs Tracking and Feature Requests</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/feedback-loop-bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/feedback-loop-bugs/</guid>
      <description>As we pointed out on the previous page, we know there are going to [occaisonal] bugs and we can expect an onslaught of feature requests.  Let&amp;#39;s make it really easy for our clients to communicate with us.  &amp;gt; Help desk software..    Fix bugs quick    Acknowledge and roadmap features    Engage in general discussions    Consider help desk software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering Unseen Improvements with Analytics</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/uncovering-unseen-improvements-with-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/uncovering-unseen-improvements-with-analytics/</guid>
      <description> This is a draft, make some great content! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call To Action - Let me Know What do You think</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/call-to-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/call-to-action/</guid>
      <description> Please Take My Survey  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Software Development Process</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/index-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/index-01/</guid>
      <description>Loosing sleep over your next software project.   Waking up in a cold sweat from a night mare about bugs, not the icky creepy crawly kind …  Sorry for the predictable, cheesy and yet, unavoidable analogy. But the reality may infact be worse than disgusting caca roaches, but things that make your customers sad and your boss mad.  Software bugs. Ick!!! Describe Symptoms  Do you wonder why programmers who are supposed to be sooo smart can&amp;#39;t seem to remember shit?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Software Development Process</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/lander02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/lander02/</guid>
      <description> TODO Put Headline here  Clear Objectives and Milestones with Kanban (PM)   If you find yourself with what feels like an excessive amount of instances of mis-communication Organization and Synchronization with Version Control (VC)  Quality Assurance with Testing with Test Driven Design (TDD)  Painless updates for happy clients with (CI/CD)  Maintain clear communication with your clients (Help Desk)  Analyze your systems and flush out bottle necks and operational waste (Analytics)  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>