<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The Process of Delivering Predictable Software on Rusty Eddy</title>
    <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in The Process of Delivering Predictable Software on Rusty Eddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rustyeddy.com/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Software is Hard</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/software-is-hard/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/software-is-hard/</guid>
      <description>Why Is Software So Difficult? Software development projects are one of the most notoriously mis-understood and broken processes. There are a number of reasons, not the least of which is the extent that software is abstract and it does abstract things, most of the time.
 One reason is that you can&amp;rsquo;t see it. Most people have no idea what programming really is There is no single right way to do software Software is a combination of Art, Science and Engineering It changes very fast  A couple having their Dream House built does not have to have to know much about construction to get a sense of how well progress is moving along on their dream house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Discovery and MVP</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/customer-discovery-and-mvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/customer-discovery-and-mvp/</guid>
      <description>This consists of one or more customer discovery sessions, where all users and owners of the software will be interviewed for their expectations, needs and desires from the upcoming software project.
The customer discovery is then turned into user stories, which are then vetted to collect the user stories. Then they are broke down into tasks that are Small, autonmous and measurable.
The test that we come up with must be completed within a day or two.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Establishing Goals and Tasks</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/goals-and-tasks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/goals-and-tasks/</guid>
      <description>Software can be properly managed just like construction projects, if the right processes and tools are established and enforced throughout the product lifecycle.
Establishing Goals and Tasks Like any project doing anything one must establish Goals, the fewer and more specific, the better.
Before any activity starts, the leaders, users, developers and everybody involved has got to be crystal clear on what their most immediate next task is.
 Read The Lean Startup to really understand how to get specific about building a product your target market will be crazy about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organinizing Software Projects with Kanban</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/kanban/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/kanban/</guid>
      <description>Expect the task list to be ever evolving. During the discovery session and defining the MVP you will begin to identify an initial set of tasks, and as the project precedes additional tasks will be realized.
Whenever and however a new task is identified, that task will be placed on the kanban board in the to do list section.
The item is ordered in the to do list according to its priority amongst the other tasks on the to do list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracking Changes to Code</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/tracking-changes-to-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/tracking-changes-to-code/</guid>
      <description>It fritens me to be introduced to a software project that has a single copy in the developers folder, or worse developers and users are manually copying folder of complex gathers of code.
If you are working like this STOP!
 Start using Version Control NOW!
 Done correctly, your VC will track every change to your source code with clear well written summaries (logs) of the problem that was solved.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clone and Branch</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/clone-and-branch/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/clone-and-branch/</guid>
      <description>This is the beginning process a developer uses to create a workspace they will make changes to the source code, add tests and possibly make other changes to the software eco-system.
In a nutshell, once a developer has a task to work on, she will essentially follow these steps:
 Get on her personal workstation Make a copy of the source code she will work on Create a branch in git such that her code does not effect anybody elses code (yet).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Software</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/testing/</guid>
      <description>Monitor Production and Bug Issues Once the applicaiton has been released into the wild, if it is to be of any success, it will start collecting a set of feature requests and gasp even bugs.
Once again, github Issues will help us track both of these. We can use Github projects to Kanban board the thing.
 Testing Unit and Systems Before her new code can be integrated into the existing, heavily trusted code base, we have to make sure it is of the same quality as the existing codebase, by adding one or more adequate tests to the systems tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peer Reviews</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/peer-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/peer-review/</guid>
      <description>Peer Review aka Pull Request Github has long since provided support for the concept of a pull request. One way to think about it is a request to pull your changes into the main line.
One great benefit it provides is the platform for new and changed code to be scrutinized reviewed.
This is the point that you can start increasing your confidence in the code, we now have tests that are passing, and we have had the code under scrutiney (peer review) it has passed both water marks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mainlining Your Vetted Code</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/commit-and-merge/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/commit-and-merge/</guid>
      <description>Github making the Commitment Now it is time for the developer to commit the changes she has made. This step is pretty simple, however we want to make sure we are doing it correctly.
When the code is merged into the main or master repository, just like commitments, it will be accomponied by the logs comments that go along with the log files.
This can provide the viewer with, literally a line by line replay of the entire history of a software development project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release Process</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/release-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/release-process/</guid>
      <description>Once the code has been commited, an action will be taken to compile a latest version of the code into a tarball and hoist upon the release server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>By the way.. Software is a Team Sport</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/team-sport/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/team-sport/</guid>
      <description>Software as a team sport. Like all other teams, it must act as a functional support system. While many teams have a Quaterback or The Driver, There is unquestionably a large number of personnel all built with specific functions to successfully deliver or accomplish the goal of the team.
No difference with software.
Programmers and sometimes management or maybe an architect are the center of attention most of the time, There is a specific need for a diverse set of skills and experiences.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>