<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Predictable IoT Software Development on Rusty Eddy</title>
    <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Predictable IoT Software Development on Rusty Eddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rustyeddy.com/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Objective and Milestones</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/objectives-and-milestones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/objectives-and-milestones/</guid>
      <description>Watch from the begining of the speech from 0:17 seconds to the 42 second mark (or if you want the whole thing. It is great).  Thank You, Arnold! I could not have said it any better! First Rule of Success ~ Have a Vision   Arnold says the First Rule of Success is to have a vision. I totally agree with that. I mean, how can you consider something a success if you haven&amp;#39;t defined what success is.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software Development Life Cycle</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/software-development-life-cycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/software-development-life-cycle/</guid>
      <description>The entire team stays in sync and consistently follow the    projects establish Software Development Life Cycle process.    Avoiding key elements of this process will accumulate technical debt that caries an interest rate that you do NOT want snowball.   Symptoms     Changes made to software are often lost    Large forklift changes frequently cause compilation problems and long integration times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Piece of Mind with Testing</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/testing/</guid>
      <description>Do not force your customers to find your bugs.    Good software becomes great when old features become more reliable and new features do resurect old bugs.    NOTE: This is when the customer set objective to the customer acceptance. Symptoms  Software is always crashing or acting unpredictable  Customers become the QA department, and get angry  Problems pop like a wack-a-mole  Testing is tedious  Testing resources are scarce and developers have very limited test time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No Hassle Updates with CI/CD</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/cicd/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/cicd/</guid>
      <description>    Give your customers their bug fixes and new features in days or weeks, not months or years.    Forklift updgrades that break stuff are not sexy. Regular small hardly noticed updates are always appreciated!   Symptoms     No idea if your systems are bleeding    No idea if you are over paying    Can not identify total bill expenses    Next: Measure and Optimize </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Feedback Loop Bugs Tracking and Feature Requests</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/feedback-loop-bugs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/feedback-loop-bugs/</guid>
      <description>   Customer engagement happens before the product is created, during all of the    the entire process (iterations) of the agile development process.    By this point, the customer engagement should be pretty well established adn that &amp;#34;bugs&amp;#34; should be handled similar to other communications.   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvements with Measurements and Analytics</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/measure-and-optimize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/measure-and-optimize/</guid>
      <description> Symptoms     Do you know if you are loosing business because of bottlenecks in your workflow?    Are you over paying for services    Do you know how efficient your system is.    Next: Join The Gang! </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call To Action - Let me Know What do You think</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/call-to-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/call-to-action/</guid>
      <description>&amp;lt;section id=&amp;#34;cta&amp;#34; class=&amp;#34;row cta-text&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;col-sm-6&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;card&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;div class=&amp;#34;card-body&amp;#34;&amp;gt; &amp;lt;h5 class=&amp;#34;card-title&amp;#34;&amp;gt;What to Expect&amp;lt;/h5&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p class=&amp;#34;card-text&amp;#34;&amp;gt;	We will cover the entire Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) process before any code is written, through the delivery and maintenance of a production piece of software. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt; &amp;lt;p class=&amp;#34;card-text&amp;#34;&amp;gt; As this series moves along, I will be demonstrating the techniques using 100% free tools and OpenSource software, such that you can easily follow along.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictable IoT Software Development</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/outline/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/outline/</guid>
      <description>Overview     Assumption: The customer is known    Assumption: The application has been vetted    Make Software Development Predictable. We want to make the software development processes predictable, to remove the mysterious schedules and never ending drain to the budget.    Right size the process: Process is essential for success. Minimizing process is essential for effeciency.    I want to document the things that make my life, as a developer easier and most important, help deliver what my customers want, on time and within bugdet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/scratch/</guid>
      <description>With at least a first slash at some milestones and goals that the entire team can huddle around. Let&amp;#39;s roll up our sleeves and get Buzzin!   But before we scatter to our cubes and bury our heads behind terminals, let&amp;#39;s all agree to get on the same page by choosing a set of tools (manual or electric) that we all are going to agree on using in a consistent and collaborative way!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Logging</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/software/logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/software/logging/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>