<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>arduino on Rusty Eddy</title>
    <link>http://rustyeddy.com/tags/arduino/</link>
    <description>Recent content in arduino on Rusty Eddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rustyeddy.com/tags/arduino/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arduino Motor Control Software</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/arduino-motor-controllers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/arduino-motor-controllers/</guid>
      <description>Pictured about is the OSEPP v2 Motor Shield which can be used as a functional replacement to the Adafruit v2 motorshield, the motorshield I recommend.
 Source code can be found here http://github.com/mobilerobot-io/arduino/ within the src/mctl directory.
 Arduino Motorsheild and Distributed Controls The software in the repository is to be loaded on an Arduino with either an Adafruit v2 Arduino or OSEPP 6612 MotorShield. The software accepts commands as incoming text strings from one of several possible serial inputs; UART, RF Radio, Blue Tooth, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inexpensive Motor Controllers for Arduino and Raspberry Pi</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/motor-controlor-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/motor-controlor-notes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I prefer to use an Arduino with a Motor Controller over say a
Raspberry Pi with a motor-controller.  I believe the Arudino has
better support for dedicated Real-time software vs. the Raspberry Pi
and as a superior platform for general computing including running
Control Software.  This is how we do it on the West side &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adafruit Music Maker mp3 Sheild</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/adafruit-music-maker-mp3-sheild/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/notes/adafruit-music-maker-mp3-sheild/</guid>
      <description>The shield is driven by an SPI connection with the Arduino and relies on an SD card with music files on it to play. Must determine how to play streaming audio, then we&amp;rsquo;ll have something neat!
Link to the documentation.
The shield can also be jumpered and booted into Midi Mode and turned into a drum machine or a Garageband type of play along, this might be fun!
I suppose we could also add a microphone to record sound for some kind of reason.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>