<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rtsp on Rusty Eddy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/rtsp/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rtsp on Rusty Eddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/rtsp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Gstreamer to create an RTSP Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/gstreamer-rtsp-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/gstreamer-rtsp-server/</guid>
      <description>Of it earlier this month I set out to start streaming video From the CSI camera, that is a raspberry pie camera, From a moving vehicle for the vehicles guidance and navigation.
I was surprised to find the the whole world is streaming video is Incredibly complex, NFL 2019 we do not have A solution that is easy universally adopted.
TLDR; Gstreamer RTSP Pipeline We are streaming our video from a Raspberry Pi Camera (CSI) attached to, either a Raspberry Pi or a Jetson Nano, GST extracts the video from the CSI camera using a custom driver (raspicamsrc or nvargussrc) for the RPi or Nano respectively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streaming Video Protocols</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/notes/streaming-video-protocols/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/notes/streaming-video-protocols/</guid>
      <description>rtp rtsp rtmp hlsl mjpeg mpeg-dash mpeg jpeg  RTP ~ Real Time Protocol Actually holds payloads containing arbitrary, but time/delay sensitive media (audio, video, live conversations, etc). Incorporates enough controls to allow for network congestion, reciever compensation and more.
RTSP What it is and How to use it Real Time Streaming Protocol (RTSP)
General consensus says that RTSP is a good choice for low latency, local area networks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>