<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Rusty Eddy</title>
    <link>http://rustyeddy.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Rusty Eddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rustyeddy.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Sensor Station</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/projects/sensor-station/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/projects/sensor-station/</guid>
      <description>SensorStation is built with an esp32 WRoom32 development board, with a temprature sensor and a standard wifi connection, it is able to periodically broadcast the local temprature via MQTT.
Features Thermo32 has the following features currently implemented:
 Temprature sampling with tmp36 Wifi connection to broadcast temprature MQTT client to advertise temprature to broker LED is flashed to indicate temprature has been sampled and broadcast. ESP-IDF / FreeRTOS, small, concurrent efficient and flexible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPA Clock</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/projects/spaclock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/projects/spaclock/</guid>
      <description>Description SPA Clock is an embedded webserver intended to run on a Rasberry Pi (or similar linux system) with a touchscreen and Internet connection.
This clock comes with Zero Touch configuration. Just plug it in, connect it to the internet and always have accurate time!
 Even through power outages and timezone changes, you&amp;rsquo;ll never have to reset your clock again.
 Now wait, that is not all! You also get other cool things like the date and current local weather!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Orange County Low Vision Website</title>
      <link>http://rustyeddy.com/projects/oclv-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rustyeddy.com/projects/oclv-website/</guid>
      <description>Orange County Low Vision is old-school when it comes to personal customer service. According to Kelly Eddy, the owner of OCLV:
 &amp;ldquo;Many of our clients are well into their 80&amp;rsquo;s and above, further more we typically do business in their homes. Trust is everything.&amp;rdquo;
 Since Personal Service and Trust have always been the foundation of OCLV &amp;ldquo;business&amp;rdquo; model, it is impairative the new website project reflect the same personable reality, yet leverage the internet to the benefit of the business and the client.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>